Making commits to a repository can be nerve wracking.
قد يكون إدخال تثبيتات إلى مستودع أمرًا محيرًا.
What if I make a mistake?
ماذا يحدث إذا ارتكبت خطأ؟
What if I want to undo something I did in the past?
ماذا لو أردت التراجع عن شيء فعلته في الماضي؟
Or what if I want to totally erase
أو ماذا لو أردت حذف
the last few commits because I'm positive they will never be used?
التثبيتات القليلة الأخيرة بالكامل بسبب تخوفي من عدم استخدامها في المستقبل؟
That's exactly what we're going to look at.
وهذا ما سننظر فيه على وجه التحديد.
In this lesson we'll look at git commit --amend,
في هذا الدرس، سننظر في الأمرgit commit --amend
git revert, and git reset.
وgit revert وgit reset.
With git commit --amend,
ومن خلال git commit --amend،
you can alter the most recent commit.
يمكنك تغيير أحدث تثبيت.
You'd want to do this if you forgot to include a file
قد ترغب في القيام بذلك إذا نسيت تضمين ملف
in the commit or had a typo in the commit message.
في التثبيت أو في حالة حدوث خطأ في رسالة التثبيت.
With git revert, you provide it the SHA of the commit that you want reverted.
ومن خلال git revert، تقوم بإدخال SHA الخاص بالتثبيت الذي تريد استرجاعه.
The changes that were made in that commit are reversed.
تم استرجاع التغييرات التي أُجريت في ذلك التثبيت.
So lines that were added in the commit will be deleted.
لذلك سيتم حذف السطور التي تمت إضافتها في التثبيت.
Don't worry though. We'll look at this in detail.
ومع ذلك لا تقلقوا. سنتعمق في ذلك بالتفصيل لاحقًا.
With git reset, you can actually delete commits.
ومن خلال git reset، يمكنك بالفعل حذف التثبيتات.
Now you can't delete just any commit.
أما الآن، لا يمكنك حذف أي تثبيت.
You have to delete commits in order.
حيث يجب عليك حذف التثبيتات بالتفصيل.
But this is a potentially dangerous command
ولكن هذا أمر يحتمل أن يكون خطرًا
because you are removing items from the repository.
لأنك تقوم بحذف عناصر من المستودع.
With these new commands, you'll have the git powers
ومن خلال هذه الأوامر الجديدة، ستحصل على قوى git
to tackle anything your job can throw at you.
لمعالجة أي شيء يمكن أن تكلفك به وظيفتك.
Let's look at git commits --amend flag.
والآن لننظر إلى git commits --علامة التعديل.